(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-05T01:44:01.870528",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
TODAY...
RAORA'S BIRTHDAY
- Chattini, let's celebrate together! -
BEGINS
[Where Emotions Bloom: Raora Panthera Birthday Live 2024]
Oh, my. That was a good nap.
Wait.
Wait a minute.
That's not my room.
Huh? Why... Why did it...
Why am I not in my room right now?
How did I end up here?
What?
A... white canvas?
Huh?
What is this?
Why... Why is there a white canvas in here?
Eh? Wh- Wh- Where is my room?
Huh?
Weird.
Chutino!
Ah! Thank God you're here!
Oh, th- this place is so scary, Chutino. Where are we?
Chutino? Chu... Chutino!
What happened to you?
Come here, don't worry. I got you.
You are kind of heavy, though.
Don't worry, Chutino, I got you.
We need to find a way out, okay?
We're going to find a way out.
Ah, where... where should we go?
Why is there a portal now?
Did you open it?
No?
Fine. I guess we should go in there.
Maybe I can wake up. Maybe I'm still dreaming.
Okay.
よいしょ。 Let's go.
Yoisho. Let's go.
You are kind of heavy, though. よいしょ。
You are kind of heavy, though. Yoisho...
ロンリーガールは いつまでも
For lonely girls, it's always the same,
届かない夢見て
dreaming dreams that won't come true,
騒ぐ頭の中を
and churning, churning
掻き回して、掻き回して。
through the clamor in their heads.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、
Muttering "I'm fine,"
言葉は失われた？
have words failed her?
もう失敗。もう失敗。
A failure, a failure,
間違い探しに終われば、
obsessing over her mistakes
また、回るの！
makes everything spin again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I'll roll along today, too,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl said, the girl said,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
breathing life into the words!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready yet?"
「まだですよ、」
"Not yet,"
「まだまだ先は見えないので」
"the future is still not in sight,"
息を止めるの、今。
"so I'll hold my breath, right now."
ローリンガールの成れの果て
The end of the rolling girl,
届かない、向こうの色
out of reach, the color on the other side.
重なる声と声を
Overlapping voice upon voice,
混ぜあわせて、混ぜあわせて。
blending together, blending together.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
"I'm fine," she muttered.
言葉は失われた。
The words were lost.
どうなったって良いんだってさ、
No matter what happens, it's fine, she says,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと、
even mistakes can be made.
誘う、坂道。
Inviting her down the slope.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私をどうか転がして」と
"Please, roll me along,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl said, the girl said,
無口に意味を重ねながら！
piling meaning onto her silence!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready yet?"
「もう少し、」
"Just a bit more,"
「もうすぐ何かが見えるだろうと」
"and we'll see something soon,"
息を止めるの、今。
"so I'll hold my breath, right now."
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I'll roll along today, too,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl said, the girl said,
言葉に笑みを奏でながら！
playing a smile on her words!
「もう良いかい？ もう良いよ。」
"Are you ready? Yes, I'm ready."
「そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ね。」
"You must be tired by now, aren't you?"
息を止めるの、今。
We'll hold our breath, right now.
Ciao!
Ah!
Oh! Yay!
Ciao everyone!
Ciao chattini!
Hi!
It's me, Raora Panthera from Hololive English Justice!
Rao!
Big... big stage!
A big... big stage!
Oh my god, look at this!
Woah...
What is this place? Why are we here?
And also, what day is it?
What... what day is it? Is it...
...is it my birthday?
Yay!
Thank you everyone for being here in... in this special day.
Thank you everyone for being here on... on this special day.
I'm so happy to see everyone!
Ciao ciao ciao ciao ciao!
Hi everyone!
And talking about my birthday...
I have a special hashtag for today, which is...
#RaoraBDay2026!
Woo!
So everyone make sure, if you want to share some screenshots...
...and you want to share some com- comments on...
...and you want to share some comments on...
...social media, make sure to use this hashtag!
Thank you so much!
Oh, but maybe now we should take a look at... we should take a look at this stage!
Woah...
It's so... it's so big, isn't it?
It's a little bit like... it looks like really dreamy, like...
It's a little bit like... it looks really dreamy, like...
...it seems like we are in a dream. Maybe... maybe I'm sleeping?
Maybe I'm sleeping? Woah...
Woah, it's like... surrealism kind of thing.
Woah, it's like... a surrealism kind of thing.
But what is this place? Where am...
Woah! Woah!
Woah! Huh?
Huh? Oh...
My... my idol outfit?
What? Huh?
Why... why am I in my idol outfit now?
Maybe that means I should sing more.
Well, might as well!
So please, listen to my song!
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promises we exchanged
目をつむり確かめる
I close my eyes to affirm it
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I will shake off the overwhelming darkness to move forward
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I ever be able to see the lost future
私ここでまた見ることできるの？
from here again?
溢れ出した不安の影を
By shattering the overflowing shadows of anxiety
何度でも裂いてこの世界歩んでこう
again and again, let's walk through this world.
とめどなく刻まれた
Time now begins to tick away incessantly
時は今始まり告げ
announcing its beginning.
変わらない
While carrying our unchanging feelings
思いをのせ
in our hearts,
閉ざされた扉開けよう
let's open the closed door!
目覚めた心は走り出した未来を描くため
My awakened heart started running to depict the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I come to a halt on a difficult road
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っててくれる
The sky always waits for me with its beautiful blue
だから怖くない
That's why I'm not afraid
もう何があっても
No matter what happens anymore,
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made.
目を閉じ確かめる
Closing my eyes, I make sure of it.
押し寄せた闇 振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the encroaching darkness and move forward.
どんなに大きな壁があっても
No matter how big the wall is in front of us,
越えてみせるからきっと
I'm sure we can overcome it.
明日信じて
Believing in tomorrow,
祈って
I pray...
壊れた世界で彷徨って私は
Wandering around in a broken world, I...
引き寄せられるように
...was drawn together,
辿り着いた
...and finally arrived.
目覚めた心は走り出した未来
My awakened heart started running
描くため
in order to paint the future.
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if we stop on a difficult path,
空は
the sky...
綺麗な青さでいつも待っててくれる
...always waits for us with its beautiful blue.
だから怖くない
So I am not afraid.
もう何があっても
No matter what happens now,
挫けない
I won't give up.
ずっと手をつないで
Holding hands forever...
Yay! Whoo! / Whoo!
Hug! Hug!
Happy birthday! / Thank you!
Thank you, Kronii! Thank you!
I'm so excited for you! It's your first 3D birthday live!
It is! And look at us with our other outfit! It's so pretty!
I know, we are so gorgeous!
So cool! I'm so cool!
You are!
I am so cool!
And you know, because you are so cool...
...I want to give you a beautiful color that I think would suit you.
Me?
Yes.
Which color? Pink? Is it going to be pink?
Um, if you look at your eyes...
...your beautiful yellow eyes...
...they have curiosity and playfulness.
And I think it suits you.
And so I would like to give this color, this beautiful color around us.
Which color?
Are you color blind?
No! You don't have to bully me on my birthday! You're supposed to be nice to me!
I meant your beautiful yellow eyes!
Ah!
It's beautiful, it's like golden.
Why? It's my birthday, instead of giving me a gift, you come here, sing and dance with me, and then just start bullying me?
You know what, get out of here!
I complimented you! I complimented...
...golden, golden eyes! Is that beautiful?
So, it's kind of like yellow, right?
Yeah, yeah!
So, what does it mean? Why did you give me this color?
Like, I just said, curiosity and playfulness.
I wasn't listening to you!
You weren't paying attention to me? You don't care about me!
My bad, you talk too much! My bad!
Sorry! I want...
I want... Sorry, I have a cold...
I think you should keep up your dream.
I have a question.
Okay! I have an answer.
Oh, yes.
Like, I was expecting blue coming from you.
Why yellow?
Why are you making me laugh?
Is it because of the yellow?
It's... it's your... it's just everything is so beautiful.
You're obsessed with my eyes.
Your eyes are so beautiful.
I was expecting blue, because I thought you were sad.
Well, you don't have a blue color scheme.
Yeah, but you're blue.
Yeah, but... / I gave you blue!
Oh, thank you!
What does that mean?
Loneliness? Sadness? Fear... maybe?
Oh... oh.
Why would you give that to me?
Because I thought you liked me.
I like you!
You invited me all the way here...
I gave you this beautiful color, and you give me blue?
But Kronii, you're so pretty like... blue!
I'm so... yeah.
And you're so pretty.
Oh, stop!
You stop!
No, you stop!
Stop!
You know what? We can blend blue and pink together...
Purple.
Yeah... never mind.
What does purple mean?
What does purple mean? I don't know, we'll find out!
Oh! Woah, purple... you just spoiled it!
We'll find out, I guess!
I don't know...
To be continued, everyone.
To be continued, everyone! So keep watching my... my... no, not our.
That's not your birthday, it's my birthday!
It is your birthday.
It is my birthday! So, we're gonna keep watching, everyone.
I'm gonna keep singing and dancing for you, okay?
And be sure to use her hashtag, okay?
Yes!
#RaoraBday2026!
Hell yeah! Yay!
Ciao ciao! Ciao ciao!
Also, thank you, Kronii, for coming!
Oh, yeah! You're welcome.
I forgot to thank you!
Thank you for singing and dancing with me! It was so much fun!
Yay!
Okay, keep up the good work!
Keep, keep up the good work!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Woo!
Ciao ciao! Ciao ciao!
Brave Shine
左手に隠した
With the wish I'd hidden away in my left hand,
願いは願いのままで
remaining a mere wish,
覚めない夢見てた
I saw an illusory dream there's no waking up from.
右手には空の記憶
In my right hand I had an empty memory...
誰も知らない世界の果て
...a world's end nobody knew anything about,
やまない雨にうたれていた
as I was assailed by a rain that wouldn't let up.
守りたいものを
The strength to be able to protect...
守れる強さ
...what you desire to...
それを信じられなくなる弱さはさ
...the weakness of losing faith in that strength...
すべてを受け入れて 未来を探す
I'll accept everything, seeking out the future.
Brave shine 手を伸ばせばまだ
Brave shine: if I stretch out my hand...
Stay the night 傷だらけの夜
Stay the night: on a night I'm covered in wounds,
You save my life かざした刃の先に
You save my life; at the tip of the blade...
想いを重ねた
...a prayer combining our feelings together...
祈りは時を越えて
...will go beyond time...
Your brave shine...
光ることも忘れた
Forgotten how to shine,
青い星が残していく
the blue stars leave behind,
消えない影見てた
I watched their undying shadows.
すれ違う赤の軌道
Red trajectories crossing each other:
何も知らない子供のまま
ignorant children,
明けない夜を彷徨ってた
they wandered through the unbreaking night.
失くせないものを
The weakness of losing...
失くした弱さ
...what you can't afford to lose,
何も信じられなくなる脆さはさ
and the fragility of losing faith in all...
立てなくなっても
Even if I can no longer stand...
...は進む
...will continue to progress.
Break down
崩れ落ちてゆく星座が
As the constellations crumble,
傷つけあう夜
on the night when they scar one another,
You're breaking dawn
交わした言葉の中に
Within the words we exchanged,
独りを支えた
they supported me when I was alone,
確かな理想（ゆめ）
supporting a certain dream...
追いかけて
as I chase after it.
守りたいものを
If I can protect
守れるのなら
what I wish to protect,
すべてを受け入れて
I will accept everything
未来（あした）を探す
and search for tomorrow.
夜明けを灯す
Lighting the dawn,
Brave shine
手を伸ばせばまだ
if I extend my hand,
Stay the night
the night remains.
傷だらけの夜
On this night covered in wounds,
You save my life
重ねた涙の果てに
At the end of these accumulated tears,
光を見つけた
I found a light.
祈りは時を
A prayer that breaks through
超えて
the barrier of time,
My brave shine
Happy Birthday, Raora!
Happy Birthday!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
Shall we introduce ourselves?
Of course, please do!
Great! 自己紹介お願いします、先輩。
Great! Please introduce yourself, Senpai.
Introduction, okay? Yes!
こんやっぴー！ホロライブ4期生の...
Kon-yappi! From Hololive 4th Generation...
えっと、オールド先輩の...
uh, the "old senpai"...
常闇トワ様でーす！イェーイ！
Tokoyami Towa-sama! Yay!
Towa Senpai! Old senpai, yay yay!
え？オールド先輩か？
Wait, "old senpai"?
Oh, really?
ちょっと待って、カリオペ is only a little bit younger in that case than Towa-sama!
Wait a minute, Calliope is only a little bit younger in that case than Towa-sama!
What? Okay, fine, hello!
え、皆さん、オールド先輩、森カリオペでーす。
Uh, everyone, I'm the "old senpai" Mori Calliope.
From Hololive English Myth, what's up, fellow pink? Fellow pink!
Pink is powerful!
え、トワ様, you're also pink!
Uh, Towa-sama, you're also pink!
Pinkish, pinkish!
Yeah, different shades of pink, right?
Yeah, the colors are so important in this life, so...
We must say that this is the pink team, right?
Pink-purple team, yeah.
Pink-purple team, お願いいたします。
Please treat the pink-purple team well!
Nice! Wonderful! But you know, the lighting actually...
...when we were singing the song that we just sang a moment ago, was blue!
Yeah, was blue!
It was blue, so pretty, right? Look at that!
What kind of emotion do you think the blue represents?
え、どんな感情？Blue.
Uh, what kind of emotion? Blue.
ブルー？
Blue?
ブルーは結構、寂しいとか...
Blue is often like sadness...
ちょっと、そういう悲しいみたいなイメージはあるけど、でも綺麗なイメージもあるよ。
It has a somewhat sad image, but also a beautiful image.
Mm, also beautiful! Sad, lonely, also beautiful.
Well, for Calliope I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? 怖さ。
Well, for Calliope I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? Fear.
Oh, a little scary, right?
But you know, emotions are beautiful, right? 感情がめっちゃ美しいと思う。
But you know, emotions are beautiful, right? I think emotions are really beautiful.
So, positive, negative, either way I think colors are really beautiful.
I agree with you! And you know, even if sometimes we have fear and we're scared of doing something, maybe...
Maybe we should overcome, we should do our best to, you know...
ま、怖くても頑張らないといけないね。
Well, even if we're scared, we have to try hard, right?
例えば, singing on stage together...
For example, singing on stage together...
...speaking Japanese! It's so scary!
な、な、意味深い。
No, no, "deep meaning."
Oh, deep meaning. That's cool.
かっこいいね。
That's cool, right?
Cute and cool, Raora.
ラオラならできる。
Raora, you can do it.
You are cool. Everyone...
Everyone here is cool.
みんなクール！
Everyone is cool!
See, pink is very cool. Pink's a cool color, okay? Hey.
Well, happy birthday to you.
Thank you so much, Mori!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
おめでとう！ Happy Birthday!
Congratulations! Happy Birthday!
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you, guys!
Thank you for singing Brave Shine with me.
It's a very meaningful song, and I really appreciate...
...to have my 大先輩s with me. Thank you so much!
...having my great senpais with me. Thank you so much!
Yeah, of course, old senpais. Old senpais here with you.
Well, myself and Towa got to get out of here, but Raora, you keep on keeping on, okay?
Okay, I'll do my best!
Yeah, and we'll see you guys later, okay?
See you guys later!
Bye, everybody!
See ya! Bye-bye!
白い世界の中では
In a white world,
時間が止まってゆくような気がした
I felt as if time was stopping.
いつも見せないような表情が
That expression you don't normally show,
その距離が 少しだけ愛しかった
and that distance, was just a little dear to me.
巻き戻せないと
Knowing we can't turn back time,
はしゃいでいるその横顔
your profile as you made merry,
抱えていた悩みも ちっぽけだ
made even my worries seem so small.
君に染まる世界が
A world dyed in your color,
かじかんでく両手が
and my numbed hands...
心から願うよ
I pray from the bottom of my heart,
終わらせたくなどはないんだと
wishing that this would never end.
思い出の中にはいつも君の姿
In my memories, your figure is always there.
夢のまま 覚めないまま その笑顔が忘れられないや
Remaining in a dream, never waking up, I can't forget that smile.
言葉では足りないようだ
Words don't seem to be enough.
大人になんてなれないよ
I can't even become an adult,
くだらない事ばっか それでも楽しかった
full of silly things, but it was still fun.
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
"I wish the present would go on like this forever,"
なんてさ僕に はにかんでみせるの
you said to me with a bashful smile,
泣きそうな声で
with a voice on the verge of tears.
新しい世界では
In this new world,
きっと心から笑えているかな
I wonder if you are laughing from the bottom of your heart.
謝りたいな
I want to apologize,
見せる顔なんてないよ
but I can't even show my face to you.
僕は君の思う未来のどこにもいないようだ
It seems I am nowhere to be found in the future you envision.
逃げ出したくないよ
I don't want to run away.
あの日に戻りたくなるよ
I find myself wanting to go back to that day.
振り向いてばかりの人生ならば 諦めよう
If life is only about looking back, let's just give up.
いたいけな祈りも
An innocent prayer,
確かめたい気持ちも
and the feelings I want to confirm...
今なら言えるだろうか
Can I say it now?
終わらせたくはないんだと知る
I realize that I don't want it to end.
何度でも言うよ
I'll say it again and again,
景色は徒に
the scenery is in vain.
足元はおぼつかない 気付けば走り出していたんだ
My steps are unsteady; before I knew it, I was running.
何度でも言うよ
I'll say it again and again,
会いたい言葉など
words like "I want to see you"...
見つかる wake でもない それでもただ信じてみたいから
I won't necessarily find them, but even so, I just want to believe.
思い出の中君の姿
In my memories, your figure...
夢のまま 覚めないまま
Remaining in a dream, never waking up...
変わらないな
It remains unchanged.
思い出の中にはいつも君の姿
In my memories, your figure is always there.
夢のまま 覚めないまま その笑顔が忘れられないや
Remaining in a dream, never waking up, I can't forget that smile.
言葉では足りないようだ
Words don't seem to be enough.
大人になんてなれないよ
I can't even become an adult,
くだらない事ばっか それでも楽しかった
full of silly things, but it was still fun.
ずっと今がこのまんま続いたらいいね
I wish now could last just like this forever...
今度は僕から繋いで見せるの
This time, I will connect us...
約束しよう
Let's make a promise.
約束をしよう
世界は終わりを告げようとしてる
The world is about to tell its end.
誰にももう止められはしない
No one can stop it anymore.
始まる
It begins...
崩壊のシンフォニーが鳴り響いて
The symphony of collapse resonates,
降る雨はまるで涙の音色
and the falling rain is like the tone of tears.
教えて
Tell me,
支配し支配され人達は
why are people, controlling and controlled,
いつかその心に憎しみを保存しようとし
someday harboring hatred in their hearts,
そして愛することを思い出せず 争うの？
and unable to remember how to love, fighting each other?
この歌が聴こえてる
Can you hear this song?
生命ある全ての者よ
To all living beings...
真実はあなたの胸の中にある
The truth lies within your heart.
嵐の海を行く時も保存するつもり
Even when sailing through stormy seas,
決して臆することのない強さを
it gives you the strength to never be daunted,
くれるから
...because it grants it to you.
けれども進むほど風は強く
Yet the further we go, the stronger the wind blows,
希望の灯はやがて消えていく
and the light of hope eventually flickers out.
「灯りをよこせ」と奪い合い
Fighting over "Give me your light,"
果てに人は殺し合う
in the end, people kill one another.
涙などとうに枯れて
With tears long since dried up...
気付いて
Please realize:
その目は互いを認めるため
Your eyes are meant to recognize one another,
その声は想いを伝えるため
your voice is meant to convey your thoughts,
その手は大事な人と繋ぐためにある
and your hands are meant to join with those important to you.
この歌が聴こえてる
Can you hear this song?
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
To all the helpless souls across the world...
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
Hope lies within your heart.
燃え盛る焔の中でも
Even amidst the blazing flames,
決して傷つくことのない強さを
it gives you the strength to never be hurt,
くれるから
...because it grants it to you.
その手で守ろうとしたものは
Was what you tried to protect with those hands
愛する者だったのだろうか
really someone you loved?
紅く染まったその手を眺めて
Looking at your hands stained crimson,
やっと自らがしてきた愚かさを
you finally realize the foolishness of what you've done,
過ちと認めるその罪を
recognize the sin as a mistake,
とめどなく溢れるその涙を知る
and know the tears overflowing endlessly.
この歌が聴こえてる
Can you hear this song?
生命ある全ての者よ
To all living beings...
想うよ
I believe...
真実は
The truth is...
あなたの胸の中にある
...inside your heart.
嵐の海を静めて
Quiet the stormy seas,
失ったものは数え切れなくとも
even if what you lost is beyond count.
この
If you...
歌が聴こえてる
...can hear this song,
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
all you helpless people of the world...
希望は
Hope...
あなたの胸の中にある
...is inside your heart.
哀しみの夜を越えるとき
When you cross this night of sorrow,
必ずあなたは生きていく強さを
you will surely find the strength to go on...
持っているから
...because you already have it.
やった！
We did it!
やった！やった！
We did it! We did it!
やった！
We did it!
Fur feet and fluffy tail?
Oh, let's show our tail!
Yes, show our tail.
Sway, sway, one, two, three...
Whoa! Mine is longer!
Mine is fluffy! Happy Birthday, Raora!
Thank you!
Thank you for being here!
Look at her! Look at her!
Look at her!
You should introduce yourself first! Who are you?
Who is this mysterious creature?
How many ears do you have?
One, two, three, four... Five? Six? Seven?
It's four! Six, seven ears!
Cute! Oh, cute!
Who are you? Introduce yourself! Stop!
Hello! Hi, chat! Hi, I'm Jeri! I'm Jerico!
And I am a four-eared fox!
And self-proclaimed best friend of the birthday girl over here!
She loves me very much, doesn't she?
I love her very much! Yeah!
Thank you so much for being here, Jeri!
Thank you for having me! It was so nice to dance with you.
I have come here today to bring you...
...a lot of passion!
...and determination!
...that you need to unleash when you do your beautiful art every single day!
I will be very passionate from now on!
I need you to unleash it now! I can't wait any longer.
Give me a pose! Give me a pose! Give me a double joint!
Unleash it! Unleash the demon!
Sorry guys, I have to go now.
Thank you so much for watching! No, no, not that!
You will continue my live!
No, no, no, no, no! Thank you so much everyone!
I'm gonna leave you! No she won't! Don't leave me.
I'm gonna leave you. Don't.
Do you know the dances for the next song?
It's gonna be very fun. You want me to join?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. No, you have to do the live now.
I have to do it live now? Already? All right.
I'm ready. Okay, okay, show me!
Show me! Show me! Whoa!
Yes! Don't listen to her, do the dance!
Dance, dance, dance! Yeah!
And now, birthday girl time!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! Hey, hey, hey, hey!
I saw that. You can't...
You can't see that! Did you see that?
No, you didn't see that! Because I saw it.
I saw it. You should see it from the stage.
Although we've been twins together, you...
You saw everything, you don't have to see anything else!
Oh god, you're so violent. That's good. The determination is coming out.
The passion is... All the passion, all the passion!
All the passion, please. I'm hyping her up, please.
Relax, I can't do that. Oh, come here, Grandma, come here.
This is okay. She wants to talk, she definitely wants to talk.
I want to talk! What do you want to talk about?
I said you want to talk. I want to talk.
You call me Grandma, how freaking dare you!
How freaking dare you! Hey!
All those moves and pull outs...
All the crazy dance... Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It was such a tough dance, wasn't it? Oh, it was so hard.
She's gonna treat me for dinner to celebrate her birthday!
Yeah, it's my birthday! Yes, yes.
You should treat me for dinner! What are you gonna get for me, birthday girl?
Actually, what are you gonna get for me? Good points here.
Oh yeah, because you guys know...
No, close the camera. No, that's fine.
I'm so not done, I'm gonna give you...
...ten dollars!
Absolutely not!
Yeah! Thank you, Ririka!
That hasn't happened!
Thank you! Thank you, thank you!
It's over! You know my data for the payment, okay?
Hey, come back! I don't want to send you money anymore!
Ah yeah, you got it. You owe me forty pounds already, mate.
Friend taxes, okay?
She's so in debt with me. This is really bad of her.
It's my birthday, I decide what I want, and I decide everything. And I want ten dollars, you're gonna give me ten dollars.
What should I do? What should I do, the drama...
Chatty, please tell her! Tell her to give me ten dollars!
You look so determined. You really want this money.
Fine, here it is! Just buy yourself some candy!
I got the ten dollars! Live on stream!
Oh my god, it's over. Oh, the mortgage! Oh, the car! Oh, the insurance!
It's okay, don't talk about negative things, because today, it's my birthday, we've got to celebrate!
Did you bring cake for us?
Ah... yes. Actually... / Where is it? The cake?
I'm waiting! / Ah, I can tell now.
Cake, cake, cake, cake! / It's in the other room!
Hey, you grabbed my tail! / Hey, hey, I grabbed your tail!
Come here! No, no, no!
It's kind of easy to do, it's very long.
Listen, listen... you need to walk... you need to run way faster if you want me to...
Oh, you know what then? I'll grab yours! / No, wait!
I'm grabbing it! I'm taking a bite!
Oh! Manager's here! / And she's not going to be happy with it.
You know what? I'm going to go and talk to your manager by myself. / No, you cannot talk to my manager! I talk to my manager!
I'm so done. I'm done. / No, you're not. Okay, actually, we're done.
That was actually a great workout. We really did deserve cake after all.
Ah, we deserve cake after all, isn't it? What's your favorite flavor?
My favorite flavor is... Ririko tail!
My favorite flavor is... Ririka's tail!
Okay, we have to go now! We have to go!
There's more to come! There's so much more! She has so many surprises for you!
You were the surprise. / Am I now? Am I now? / But I have more surprises. / She does, she does.
So thank you so much, Ririka! / Ririka! / Thank you for having me!
Pink creature! Pink creature! / Big grey creature!
Oh, yes! Actually, talking about colors, she's also put some colors on.
Oh, I have some new glasses then, nice and red! You should see them... I'll show you sometime soon!
More songs! More songs to come! Happy Birthday!
Thank you, Ririka! Happy Birthday!
Okay, then! Ta-ta! Bye-bye!
言って。
Say it.
あのね、私実は気付いてるの
Hey, you know what? Actually, I've realized it already.
ほら、君がいったこと
About what you said back then.
あまり考えたいと思えなくて
I didn't want to think about it too much,
忘れてたんだけど
so I just ended up forgetting.
盲目的に盲動的に妄想的に生きて
Living so blindly, so recklessly, and so delusionally,
衝動的な焦燥的な消極的なままじゃ駄目だったんだ
Staying so impulsive, so impatient, and so passive— I knew that just wouldn't do anymore.
きっと人生最後の日を前に思うのだろう
I'm sure before the final day of my life, I'll think...
全部全部言い足りなくて惜しいけど
...that it's regrettable I didn't get to say everything, everything.
あぁ いつか人生最後の日 君がいないことを
Ah, someday on the last day of my life, that you are not here...
もっと もっと もっと もっと
More, more, more, more...
もっと ちゃんと言って
...more, properly say it.
あのね
Hey, you know...
空が青いのってどうやって
...how should I convey the blueness of the sky...
伝えればいいんだろうね
...I wonder?
夜の
At night...
雲が高いのってどうすれば
...what should I do so you can also get...
君もわかるんだろう
...just how high the clouds are?
言って
Say it.
あのね
Hey, you know...
私実はわかってるの
...I actually already know...
もう君がいったこと
...that you are already gone.
あのね
Hey, you know...
わからずやって言うんだろうね
...you'll probably call me a stubborn blockhead, right?
忘れたいんだけど
I want to forget, but...
もっとちゃんと言ってよ
More, tell me properly.
忘れないようメモにしてよ
Make a memo so I don't forget.
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかしよう
Let's meet at 10 o'clock tomorrow on the platform, or something like that.
牡丹は散っても花だ
Even if the peony petals scatter, it's still a flower.
夏が去っても追慕は切だ
Even if summer is gone, the yearning is earnest.
口に出して
Put it into words.
声に出して
Say it out loud.
君が言って
You say it.
そして人生最後の日 君が見えるのなら
And on the last day of my life, if I am able to see you...
きっと人生最後の日も愛をうたうのだろう
...surely I'll be singing my love on the last day of my life as well.
全部全部無駄じゃなかったって言うから
I'll say none of it, none of it ended up being for nothing, so...
あぁ いつか人生最後の日 君がいないことが
Ah, someday on the last day of my life, that you are gone...
まだ信じられないけど
...I still won't be able to believe, but...
もっと もっと もっと もっと
More, more, more, more...
もっと もっと もっと 君が
...more, more, more, you...
もっと もっと もっと もっと
...more, more, more, more...
もっと ちゃんと言って
...more, properly say it.
うわー！ イェーイ！
Woo! Yay!
イェーイ！
Yay!
Oh, thank you! Thank you so much for being here, Mio-senpai, Okayu-senpai!
イェーイ！
Yay!
I can't believe we sang together!
So fun!
Yeah, us too! Thank you!
Thank you! Thank you!
最初のゲストは、みお先輩とおかゆ先輩です！
Our first guests are Mio-senpai and Okayu-senpai!
イェーイ！ らーら、ハッピーバースデー！
Yay! Raora, happy birthday!
ハッピーバースデー！ Oh, thank you!
Happy birthday! Oh, thank you!
おめでとう！ ありがとう！ ありがとう！
Happy birthday! Thank you! Thank you!
Ah, thank you! 来てくれてありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you! Thank you so much for coming!
こちらこそ！
Likewise!
Ah, mind introducing yourselves one more time?
自己紹介お願いします！
Please introduce yourselves!
おっけー！
Okay!
うちうち！ うちだよ！ 大神ミオだよ！
Hey there! It's me, Ookami Mio!
ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオです！
I'm Ookami Mio from Hololive Gamers!
わぁ、可愛い！
Wow, so cute!
そして！
And next!
はーい！ もぐもぐ、おかゆ！
Hi there! Munch munch, Okayu!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです！
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
もぐもぐおかゆ先輩！ もぐもぐ！
Munch munch Okayu-senpai! Munch munch!
Um, I'm gonna eat you up! Yummy yummy!
Yummy yummy!
Thank you so much! ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you!
よ、よし！ 行くぞ！
Alright! Let's do this!
えーと、ミオズ・イングリッシュ・チャレンジ！
Next up, Mio's English Challenge!
うわー！
Woo!
The glow light in the concert was beautiful, wasn't it?
The glow lights in the concert were beautiful, weren't they?
イェーイ！フゥー！
Yeah! Woo!
オッケー、やるぞ。イングリッシュ チャレンジ！
Okay, let's do... English challenge!
フゥー！
Woo!
Uh, she symbolise sincerity and self-accepting.
And you don't have to try to be strong or try to be perfect.
おおー！ / That's right!
Ooooh! / That's right!
Just accept yourself as you are and go with the flow and you'll be fine.
あぁー！ Can I be strong? Strong, strong, strong, strong?
Ah! Can I be strong? Strong, strong, strong, strong?
I wanna be a strong big cat!
Big cat! Yes!
ラオーラは強い猫。 / ラオーラは強い猫。
Raora is a strong cat. / Raora is a strong cat.
Thank you, senpais, for your nice words! Thank you!
ありがとうー！ / ありがとう！
Thank you! / Thank you!
心に響きました。
It touched my heart.
よかったわー。 / よかったよかった。
I'm so glad. / Good, good.
And... from here...
I've got some exciting news for you guys!
It's about Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026!
イェーイ！フゥー！
Yay! Woo!
So, please, senpais, help me out, okay?
オッケー！グッズ紹介、お手伝いします！任せて！
Okay! I'll help introduce the merch! Leave it to us!
Okay, so... Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026...
Goods... no, merch details!
おお、グッズ！ / よろしくお願いします！
Oh, merch! / We look forward to it!
Okay, okay, let's go, let's go, let's go! Let's go!
Yo, take a look here!
こちらどうぞ！ / おおー！すごいね！
Here you go! / Ooh! Amazing!
So good! Look at this illustration! Do you like it?
うん、好き！ / おお、すごい可愛い！ね、可愛いよ！
Yeah, I love it! / Oh, so cute! Right, so cute!
The illustration was drawn by Komiya-sensei!
Thank you so much for making this beautiful art! I'm so happy!
こみや先生に描いてもらったみたいです！
It looks like Komiya-sensei drew this!
ライブの、ライブのラオーラをテーマに描いてもらったみたいですね！
It seems she drew it with a live performance theme!
Okay, so let's take a closer look at the details!
First up, this one!
わぁー！ / おおー！
Wow! / Ooh!
B-Day Live Long T-Shirt!
ロンTだ！ロンTシャツ！ロンTシャツ！
It's a long sleeve T-shirt! Long T-shirt!
It features my motif logo on the back...
...and there's also design on the sleeves, so it's really, really cool for everyday life!
おー、素敵ー！可愛い！
Oh, lovely! So cute!
ね、なんかロゴとかも付いててね、いっぱいデザインが凝ってて可愛い！
Right, it has logos and stuff, so much detailed design, so cute!
And next, we have... Ta-da!
Panthera Crossbody Bag!
おお、ボディバッグ！ボディバッグ！ボディバッグ！
Oh, body bag! Body bag! Body bag!
And it's a bag designed for everyday use that lets you show off your love for...
...Me-ka!
...Big cat!
ビキャ！ビキャ、ビキャ！
Big cat! Big cat!
ラオーラ推しがアピールできる、普段使いできるバッグになっております！
It's a bag you can use daily while showing off your love for Raora!
ありがとう！ Next up is... Ta-da!
Thank you! Next up is... Ta-da!
Punished Chattini Plushie Keychain!
おお、Chattiniだ！ Chattiniのキーホルダー！
Oh, Chattini! Chattini keychain!
罰されたChattini！ Punished Chattini! That's what you deserve! That's what you got!
Punished Chattini! Punished Chattini! That's what you deserve! That's what you got!
Sorry, sorry! That's what you got... / まあまあまあ、まあまあまあ
Sorry, sorry! That's what you got... / Now, now, now...
The Punished Chattini that comes with... an amazing pouch!
Next, please! / Next, please! Wow!
Washing Machine Pouch! Perfect! You can combine them together!
Chattiniが洗濯機の中に閉じ込められちゃったみたいです！
It looks like Chattini got trapped inside the washing machine!
回しちゃう、回しちゃう、Chattiniを。ぐるぐるぐるー。
Spinning, spinning Chattini. Round and round.
はい、こちらね、Chattiniが閉じ込められてるのは、ぬいぐるみ用のマルチポーチですね！すごい可愛い！
Yes, here, Chattini being trapped inside is a multi-pouch for plushies! So cute!
And next up is... Ta-da!
Voice Pack!
It's gonna be fun to listen to it, so please check it out! / Thank you! Thank you!
はい、ラオーラが収録頑張って収録したボイス、聞いてみてくださいね！皆さんね！
Yes, please listen to the voice pack Raora worked so hard to record, everyone!
And there's also bonus for purchasing... the full set! And here it is!
The limited quantity items are... cheki-style photo with...
直筆メッセージ、サイン。うん。
A written message, and an autograph, yes.
サイン、サイン！
Autograph, autograph!
おっ、こちらは直筆サイン入りのチェキ風ブロマイドカードがフルセットについてきます！
Oh, this one comes with an autographed instant photo-style bromide card in the full set!
おー！すごーい！
Oh! Amazing!
And cheki-style bro- bromide...
And instant photo-style bro- bromide...
English 難しい！
English is hard!
English 難しかった？
Was English hard?
難しい！ディフィカルト イングリッシュ！
Hard! Difficult English!
With foil-stamped repr- reproduction, repr- repr- I can... I can't talk anymore. Signature, woo!
わー！
Wow!
ちなみにサインは数量限定となっております！
By the way, the autographed ones are limited in quantity!
はい！
Okay!
お願いします。
Please check it out.
お願いします！
Please check it out!
So here is the full set again, so please go check it out, everyone! Thank you, thank you!
And that was the merch line-up for Raora Panther's Birthday Celebration 2026!
Thank you so much!
Mio-senpai, Okayu-senpai...
...thank you so much for your support! Thank you so much!
いいえ、こちらこそ！
No, thank you as well!
上手にフォローできてたかな？どうかな？できてたかな？
I wonder if we supported you well? How was it? Did we do well?
うふふ！
Haha!
でも、すっごく楽しかったです！
But it was so much fun!
楽しかった！すっごくハッピー！
It was fun! So happy!
楽しかった！ありがとう、嬉しい！
It was fun! Thank you, I'm so happy!
All right, now that the merch announcement is done...
...the next song will be the last one, 最後！
...the next song will be the last one, the last!
えー！最後の曲！？
Eh! The last song?!
Last song.
わー！楽しみ！
Wow! I'm looking forward to it!
I'm kind of nervous.
Please cheer for me, okay, Senpais?
うん！オッケー、オッケー！
Yeah! Okay, okay!
頑張れ、頑張れ！ファイト、ラオラ！ありがとう！
Do your best, do your best! Fight, Raora! Thank you!
じゃあ、ばいばい、Let's say goodbye? オッケー、オッケー！
Well then, bye-bye, let's say goodbye? Okay, okay!
ばいばーい！ばいばーい！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
Draw.
作詞・編曲：Orcaにゃん
[Song: Draw. / Lyrics, Music Arrangement: Orcaにゃん]
夢のぬくもりと
With the warmth of a dream...
指先に絵の具の匂い
...and the scent of paint on my fingertips.
湿ったキャンバスの上には
Upon the damp canvas,
まだ知らない色が息をする
...colors I have yet to know draw their breath.
All the pieces I picked up
Unravel in my own chest
"It's okay," I whisper softly
At last, hold my true colors
ほどけた輪郭も
Even the unraveled outline,
そっと、ずっと、重なって
gently, always overlapping,
私の形になる
starts to take my own shape.
静かな始まりに
In this quiet beginning,
目覚めた色を抱いて
embracing the awakened colors.
I'm drawing out my true colors
滲んだ輪郭も
Even the blurred outline,
淡く、脆く、煌めいて
faintly, fragilely, sparkling,
形になってゆくの
starts to take shape.
夜明けの面影を
The traces of dawn,
集めた色で描く
I paint with the colors I've gathered.
Draw it slow, draw it true
Ah-ah-ah
La la la
Draw it slow, draw it true
夢のぬくもりと
The warmth of dreams,
指先に絵の具の匂い
and the scent of paint on my fingertips.
ありふれた朝の先には
Beyond the ordinary morning,
まだ知らない色が溢れてる
colors I don't know yet are overflowing.
Raooo!
Ciao, everyone! I'm still here.
Ah, um, I just wanted to say
thank you so, so much for watching my first ever birthday live!
I had so much fun, and I hope you... I hope you had so, so much fun too!
I worked really, really hard, and I'm so happy right now. So...
Thank you, Chattini! Thank you, everyone, for watching!
見てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for watching!
So, I have to go now. Bye-bye!
And remember: big cat means...
big trouble! Raooo!
Raooo!
Ciao, everyone! I have one last message for you all.
Be sure to check out the MV premiere right after this!
And also, my new original song will be releasing on all streaming platforms on May 11th at midnight...
...in your local time zone!
So don't miss out, okay? Also, go check out my merch! Bye-bye!
Raooo! Bye-bye!